Swaminathan Sankararaman

Application Support Analyst

• Chennai, TN, India • swaminathan.sr4@gmail.com • +91-81220-29364 • LinkedIn • GitHub

Summary _

I am an IT Analyst with Tata Consultancy Services Ltd., with employment experience close to 6 years. I am working as an Application support Analyst for a leading banker in North America. My roles and responsibilities include testing and performance monitoring for a client proprietary file transfer tool during OS patching or uprgade on the application server or during a new version upgrade of the tool. I am also incharge of testing proof of concepts to check for performance improvement of newly introduced solutions, to consider if the implementation of the proposed solution is viable or not. I am looking for opportunites to pursue the role of a Performance Engineer for Software Applications.

Work Experience ___

• Tata Consultancy Services India Ltd., Chennai, TN, India Application Support Analyst

- August 2023 Present
- Developing test plan and testing client proprietary file transfer tool.
- Developing python scripts to perform file delivery and validate the transfer in cleint proprietary file transfer tool across different versions of tool to ensure consistency.
- Perform tests to validate if there any performance improvement when the new optional features or functionalities are introduced.
- Setting up alerts and monitors in application servers using Dynatrace. This was essential during load-testing in lower environments to prevent impact for the other users.
- Deployed automated test scripts using Ansible.
- Generated reports on user compliance to the policies set by the Application Engineering team to identify gaps and potential opportunities to improve the tool provided.
- Tata Consultancy Services Canada Ltd., Toronto, ON, Canada Application Support Analyst

March 2022 - July 2023

- Created accounts to enable secure file transfer within and outside the organization.
- Developed Job Information Language (JIL) to automate the file transfer and file receiving process.
- Succeeded in creating Unix scripts to aid file transfer through automated process.
- Performed Incident management and Change management services for the Client.
- Tata Consultancy Services India Ltd., Chennai, TN, India Software Developer, Systems Engineer

January 2017 - December 2019

- Developed driver programs capable of creating credit card invoice files for 20 clients, payment processing jobs for 5 clients and bill transmission jobs for over 50 clients of a Global Financial Institution.
- Developed a driver program using COBOL to generate credit card invoice files in a standard file format from unstructured data received from over 20 clients by a leading bank.
- Developed jobs to process payments for 5 clients using Job Control Language (JCL)
- Scheduled commercial credit card bill transmission jobs for more than 50 clients matching their payment cycle.
- Developed a tracking system for a large client to keep track of their commercial credit card invoices.
- Tracker system combined the results from over 50 different jobs and delivered the client a dash board containing necessary details
- Optimized the production environment by removing over 30 obsolete jobs which costing the client and unnecessary overhead.
- Analyzed over 100s of jobs to identify their dependencies and links in the system to weed out unnecessary jobs from the test and production systems completely to optimize the environment.

Certifications

 Microsoft Azure Data Fundamentals Certified – DP900 Credential ID: 42D01F87BCCA2F5 Certification No:. 5C75D2-08K458

Education

 \bullet University of Guelph, Guelph, ON, Canada

Master of Engineering, Engineering Overall CGPA: 3.4/4.0

Relevant Courses: Machine Learning, Data Analysis, Intelligent Real-Time Systems, Internet of Things

• Sri Sairam Engineering College, Chennai, TN, India

August 2012 - April 2016 Overall CGPA: 7.98/10.0

• JCL

July 2020 - August 2021

Bachelor of Engineering, Engineering

Relevant Courses: Data Structures, Object Oriented Programming, Computer Programming

Technical Skills

Programming Languages

Python • SQL • Scala • R • Julia • COBOL • C • C++
• Git • Jupyter Notebook • VS Code • PyChar • R Studio • Vin

Developer Tools Analytics Tool Git Jupyter Notebook VS Code PyChar R Studio Vim
 Microsoft Power BI MS Excel Numpy Pandas Seaborn Matplotlib

Microsoft Power BIMS ExcelNumpyScikit-LearnSparkDynatraceDatadog

Operating System • Windows • Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) • Unix like OS

Soft Skills

• Problem Solving • Adaptability • Critical Thinking • Learning from others • Communication • Teamwork